Evil will surface.
The Burrowers is a horror, western film directed by J.T. Petty.
It is 1879 in the Dakota Territories, a band of men who set out to find and recover a
family of settlers that has mysteriously vanished from their home.
Expecting the offenders to be a band of fierce natives, but they soon
discover that the real enemy stalks them from below.
Henry Victor, played by Doug Hutchison.
John Clay, played by Clancy Brown.
Will Parcher, played by William Mapother.
Coffey, played by Karl Geary.
Maryanne, played by Jocelin Donahue.
Gertrude, played by Laura Leighton.
The Burrowers is a 2008 American Western horror film written and directed by J.
It stars Clancy Brown, William Mapother, Karl Geary,
Sean Patrick Thomas, and Doug Hutchison.
Set in 1879, the film follows a rescue party in search of a family whose mysterious
vanishing brings them face to face with deadly tunnel-boring creatures.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 9, 2008,
before being released direct-to-DVD by Lionsgate on April 21, 2009.
It received positive reviews from critics, with praise directed towards the
story, Petty's direction, and its blending of film genres.
The film explores themes of monster, funeral,
underground, dakota, native american.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.